# **Erin C. Otterstrom**

Cottonwood Heights, UT 84121 | Phone: (801)898-6834 | Email: erinotterstrom@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://ecotterstrom.github.io/portfolio

GitHub: ECOtterstrom | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/erinotterstrom

### Summary

Enterprising software engineer with skills both the front end and back end of web applications. Experienced in researching and resolving customer issues, writing SQL queries for data mining, authoring technical documents, and I.T. project management. Enthusiastic team player with a strong work ethic, advanced complex problem-solving skills, and a willingness to take on added responsibility to meet tight deadlines.

#### **Technical Skills**

JavaScript, React, MongoDB, SQL, JQuery, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, APIs, JSON, AJAX, Express.

### **Projects**

Utah Views Live - https://utahviews.herokuapp.com/ | GitHub - ECOtterstrom/UTAHVIEWS

- An app designed for finding hiking trails in Utah. Cities dropdown enables users to select a Utah city, then the app displays hiking trails within 25 miles of that city. It also allows users to sign in.
- **Tools used**: React, JSX, API, Passport, MongoDB, Bootstrap.

Quaransale Live - https://parkersproject.herokuapp.com/ | GitHub - MartinMartinez83/Project2

- An app designed for creating online garage sales. It allows the sellers to create and post garage sales from home during quarantine. It also enables buyers to browse items for sale by the seller.
- Tools used: JQuery, SQL, Passport, Handlebars, Bootstrap.

W&C Truck du Vin Live - https://ecotterstrom.github.io/wnctruck/ | GitHub - ECOtterstrom/wnctruck

- An app designed for a wine and cheese food truck. The application provides a map with the location of the truck, a menu, an online ordering page, and a page where the cooks can receive customer orders.
- **Tools used**: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, API, Materialize, Bootstrap.

## **Experience**

L3 Technologies Salt Lake City, UT
Business Process Analyst 2013 - 2019

- Managed a log of break fixes, enhancements, change requests, and maintenance tasks for HR.
- Wrote SQL queries to mine data to resolve business customer issues and validate against SAP.
- Responsible for writing test plans and performing unit and integration testing on multiple SAP upgrades.

## **International Agreements Administrator**

2010 - 2013

- Managed all international agreements with Consultants, Distributors, and Representatives (CDRs) for the division.
- Designed the division process for performing due diligence on international subcontractors.
- Drafted international agreements, performed due diligence on CDRs, and managed CDR payments.

### **Business Analyst / Implementation Team Lead**

2006 - 2010

- Created and maintained implementation project schedules and led project meetings.
- Documented project requirements, wrote design specifications, and ensured requirements were fulfilled.
- Acted as a liaison between I.T. Shared Services and the business units.
- Researched and resolved user problems with Ceridian and the Source 550 database.

### **Education and Training**

#### University of Utah Coding Bootcamp, Salt Lake City, UT

Certificate - August 2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js and React.

Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Alliance

August 2016

#### University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

Juris Doctor (JD), Master of Business Administration (MBA), and Bachelor of Science (BS) in Economics, cum laude.